A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Monographs FA951
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Monographs
1904-1930
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University Press
FA951
4 Cubic Feet 7 document boxes and 1 flat box.
7 document boxes and 1 flat box.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Arrangement
The Rockefeller University Monographs are arranged by monograph number; chronological.
Custodial History
Duplicate copies of the monographs were received from Eric Meyerhoff, Librarian, Cornell University Medical College in 1984.
Scope and Contents
Between 1904 and 1930 certain researches were selected for publication as individual monographs. They were issued in a numbered series entitled The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research Monographs.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 544
Medical technology; Medical education; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Life sciences; Biology -- Research; Medical research; Medicine, Preventive; Science -- Study and teaching; Medical sciences; Rockefeller University Press
- The Rockefeller Instiute for Medical Research Monographs, 1904-1930; 4 Cubic Feet
  - Monograph [0] - Simon Flexner and L. Emmett Holt, eds. - "Bacteriological and Clinical Studies of the Diarrheal Diseases of Infancy with Reference to the Bacillus Dysenteriæ (Shiga)", 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Monograph 1 - Simon Flexner, J.W. Jobling, and Maud L. Menten - "Studies Upon a Transplantable Rat Tumor" [Copy 1], 1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Also Includes:
    J.W. Jobling, "The Biology of a Mixed Tumor of the Rat" - Maud L. Menten, "Experiments on the Influence of Radium Bromide on a Carcinomatous Tumor of the Rat" - J.W. Jobling, "Spontaneous Tumors of the Mouse" - J.W. Jobling, "Transplantation Experiments in Macacus Rhesus with a Carcinomatous Teratoma from Man"
  - Monograph 1 - Simon Flexner, J.W. Jobling, and Maud L. Menten - "Studies Upon a Transplantable Rat Tumor" [Copy 2], 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Monograph 2 - William Travis Howard and Oscar T. Schultz - "Studies in the Biology of Tumor Cells", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Monograph 2 - William Travis Howard and Oscar T. Schultz - "Studies in the Biology of Tumor Cells" [Copy 2], 1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Monograph 3 - B.T. Terry - "Chemo-Therapeutic Trypanosome Studies with Special Reference to the Immunity Following Cure" [Copy 1], 1911 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Monograph 3 - B.T. Terry - "Chemo-Therapeutic Trypanosome STudies with Special Reference to the Immunity Following Cure" [Copy 2], 1911 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Monograph 4 - Francis W. Peabody, George Draper, and A.R. Dochez - "A Clinical Study of Acute Poliomyelitis" [Copy 1], 1912 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Monograph 4 - Francis W. Peabody, George Draper, and A.R. Dochez - "A Clinical Study of Acute Poliomyelitis" [Copy 2], 1912 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Monograph 5 - J.P. Simonds - "Studies in Bacillus Welchii, with Special Reference to Classification and to Its Relation to Diarrhea", 1915 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Monograph 6 - James L. Stoddard and Elliott C. Cutler - "Torula Infection in Man", 1916 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Monograph 7 - Oswald T. Avery, H.T. Chickering, Rufus Cole, and A.R. Dochez, "Acute Lobar Pneumonia: Prevention and Serum Treatment" [Copy 1], 1917 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Monograph 7 - Oswald T. Avery, H.T. Chickering, Rufus Cole, and A.R. Dochez, "Acute Lobar Pneumonia: Prevention and Serum Treatment" [Copy 2], 1917 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Monograph 8 - Ernest Dickson, "Botulism: A Clinical and Experimental Study", 1918 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Monographs 4 and 8 - Francis W. Peabody, George Draper, A.R. Dochez, and Ernest Dickson, "A Clinical Stody of Acute Poliomyelitis" and Botulism: A Clinical and Experimental Study", 1912, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Monograph 9 - James Howard Brown, "The Use of Blood Agar for the Study of Streptococci" [Copy 1], 1919 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Monograph 9 - James Howard Brown, "The Use of Blood Agar for the Study of Streptococci" [Copy 2], 1919 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Monograph 10 - William G. MacCallum, "The Pathology of the Pneumonia in the United States Army Camps during the Winter of 1917-1918" [Copy 1], 1919 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Monograph 10 - William G. MacCallum, "The Pathology of the Pneumonia in the United States Army Camps during the Winter of 1917-1918" [Copy 2] (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Monograph 11 - Frederick M. Allen, Edgar Stillman, and Reginald Fitz, "Total Dietary Regulation in the Treatment of Diabetes" [Copy 1], 1919 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Monograph 11 - Frederick M. Allen, Edgar Stillman, and Reginald Fitz, "Total Dietary Regulation in the Treatment of Diabetes" [Copy 2], 1919 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Monograph 12 - Lewis H. Weed, Paul Wegeforth, James B. Ayer, and Lloyd D. Felton, "A Study of Experimental Meningitis: A Series of Papers from the Army Neuro-Surgical Laboratory", 1920 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Monograph 13 - Werner Marchand, "The Early Stages of Tabandæ (Horse-Flies)" [Copy 1], 1920 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Monograph 13 - Werner Marchand, "The Early Stages of Tabanidæ (Horse-Flies)" [Copy 2], 1920 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Monograph 14 - S.T. Darling and W.G. Smillie, "Studies on Hookworm Infection in Brazil" [Copy 1], 1921 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Monograph 14 - S.T. Darling and W.G. Smillie, "Studies on Hookworm Infection in Brazil" [Copy 2], 1921 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Monograph 15 - I.J. Kligler, "Investigation on Soil Pollution and the Relation of the Various Types of Privies to the Spread of Intestinal Infections" [Copy 1], 1921 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Monograph 15 - I.J. Kligler, "Investigation on Soil Pollution and the Relation of the Various Types of Privies to the Spread of Intestinal Infections” [Copy 2], 1921 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Monograph 16 - Abraham L. Garbat, "Typhoid Carriers and Typhoid Immunity" [Copy 1], 1922 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Monograph 16 - Abraham L. Garbat, "Typhoid Carriers and Typhoid Immunity" [Copy 2], 1922 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Monograph 17 - Wilson G. Smillie, "Studies on Hookworm Infection in Brazil, 1918-1920", 1922 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Monograph 18 - P.A. Levene, "Hexosamines, Their Derivatives, and Mucins and Mucoids" [Copy 1], 1922 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Monograph 18 - P.A. Levene, "Hexosamines, Their Derivatives, and Mucins and Mucoids" [Copy 2], 1922 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Monograph 19 - Theobald Smith and Ralph B. Little, "Studies in Vaccinal Immunity towards Disease of the Bovine Placenta due to Bacillus Abortus (Infectious Abortion)" [Copy 1], 1923 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Monograph 19 - Theobald Smith and Ralph B. Little, "Studies in Vaccinal Immunity towards Disease of the Bovine Placenta due to Bacillus Abortus (Infection Abortion)" [Copy 2], 1923 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Monograph 20 - Hideyo Noguchi, "Experimental Studies of Yellow Fever in Northern Brazil" [Copy 1], 1924 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Monograph 20 - Hideyo Noguchi, "Experimental Studies of Yellow Fever in Northern Brazil" [Copy 2], 1924 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Monograph 21 - James B. Murphy, "The Lymphocyte in Resistance to Tissue Grafting, Malignant Disease, and Tuberculosis Infection: An Experimental Study", 1926 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Monograph 22 - Harvey Cushing and Leo M. Davidoff, "The Pathological Findings in Four Autopsied Cases of Acromegaly with a Discussion of their Significance", 1927 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Monograph 23 - Louise Pearce, "The Treatment of Human Trypanosomiasis with Tryparsamide: A Critical Study" [Copy 1], 1930 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Monograph 23 - Louise Pearce, "The Treatment of Human Trypanosomiasis with Tryparsamide: A Critical Study" [Copy 2], 1930 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Supplementary Materials - Werner Marchand, "Studies on Larval Stages of North-American Tabanidæ (Horse-Flies)" (Box 7, Folder 42, Folder 43, Folder 44, Box 8, Folder 45)